Spectrum development here helps AI here
to plan things before doing
implementation. And on this channel we
have reviewed tons of spectrum of
frameworks. So that's why in this video
we're going to take a look at the most
popular spectrum development frameworks
that we have like superpower, G stack,
GSD, and we're going to take a look at
how we can piece them all together into
a single workflow that we're going to
use to building applications with the
highest accuracy. And most importantly,
we're going to take this one step
further. We're going to introducing the
route loop here to see how we can be
able to build this applications
completely autonomous. Or we're going to
have Clocko here to using Clocko
headless where I can spin up different
iterations and each iteration here can
be able to call like superpower, G
stack, GSD, and all the scales, all the
MCP servers that we have and try to
having it orchestrator here to loop
through until we have the project is
fully built. So we can do this
completely autonomous using the route
loop approach and also achieve the
highest accuracy extract by extracting
all the best skills from each frameworks
and pieces all together into our own
workflows. So pretty much that's what
we're going to cover in this video and
if you're interested, let's get into the
video. Now before we continue, I
recently launched our school community
where I help you to master AI agents,
automations, and so much more. And
that's all coming from someone who used
to work as a senior AI software engineer
at companies like Amazon and Microsoft.
And in this community, you're going to
get over 100 plus video materials like
templates and workflows that I
personally built and sold over 100 plus
times. On top of that, you also going to
get access to our weekly live calls. And
just give you an idea, this week we're
actually running a Clocko masterclass
where we're going to dive into how to
improve Clocko's accuracy when we're
going to use it to building
applications. Plus you're also going to
get full community supports where you're
going to get chance to ask questions and
get direct answers back. So if you're
ready to level up, make sure you drop
right in and I'll see you in the
community. All right, so in order to
understand how we can be able to piece
all those workflows together, let's
understand what spectrum development
does, right? So for spectrum development
here, it basically help you to or help
AI here to plan things before doing
executions and we all know that. But
essentially, this is the workflow that
most spectrum development here follows.
It doesn't matter if it's spec kit, the
B map method, or you know, any other XYZ
framework. They always go with something
like brainstorming, right? Helping you
to clarify what you're trying to build.
Then it's going to go down to like
planning, right? How exactly we're going
to execute this? Maybe a task list, or
maybe breaking this task into different
phases, and each phase has its own task
list. And then eventually it's going to
go down to executions, and eventually
here has review, has verifications,
maybe having using Playwright here to
spin up another browser agent here to
verify everything, right? So, you can
see that this is the entire spectrum of
workflows that pretty much most uh
frameworks here follows. And
essentially, how each framework here
different is that for Superpower here,
like you can see for each one, what's
special about each one is that for
Superpower, it's really good at focusing
on test-driven developments, which is
something that other workflow doesn't
have. It's focusing on writing test
first before it do the implementation.
And then for G-stack, it's a little
different. It also follow that
framework, but the selling point here
for G-stack is that it's focusing on
role-based, which has like different
CEO, designers, engineer managers,
or maybe security manager here, try to
integrate with different personalities
here, try to help you to decide a best
decision for your product, right? Maybe
you're still in the planning phase, or
maybe brainstorming phase, it's going to
help you to dive deep and try to help
you to identify that, right? And
furthermore, we also have GSD, which it
will help us to avoid context rot. And
just to give you a quick TLDR what uh
the context rot means, if you have ever
interact with large language model,
usually it will start to become pretty
accurate at uh before 50% of the context
window, right? Maybe after you surpass
like 50% of the context, it will start
to become lower for the accuracy, right?
That's exactly what context rot means,
is that the more you talk to the AI in
the same context, the lower the accuracy
it start become. And that's exactly what
GSD is trying to solve, is that to make
sure that each time when you interact
with Claude code or any other coding
agents, it's going to make sure that you
stay under 50% for the context window.
And that's exactly what GSD does. And
you can see that with all the special
power listed from each frameworks, we
can now be able to take the best out of
each frameworks and try to piece it
together into our own spectral framework
that will help you to build applications
here much more accurate, right? So,
that's exactly how I would do it to take
the best out of all three and try to
place it into the right workflow, right?
So, you can see that this is the exact
workflow that I use. I use G stack here
to do better brainstorming for clarify
my intent on exactly what I'm building
because that's what G stack is really
good for. And I'll basically put this
for this uh planning phase. And then
once we have our spec down, once we are
using G stack here to clarify our
intent, create our spec, then we're
using G stack, sorry, GSD here to
basically taking our spec and break it
down into different phases. And the
reason why we do this is like I said,
the context fraud issue, right? We don't
want to put the entire spec into claw
code and have it to execute everything.
We want to break it down into different
phases. And each phase will guarantee
claw code here is going to stay under
50% and that's it. And this will give us
the highest accuracy when we
um delegate each phase to the claw
headless or claw session to do the
execution, right? And eventually here
you can see after we break it down into
different phases, we're going to using
Superpower here to follow test-driven
developments here to doing the execution
for each phase. And that's exactly how I
would do it if you were to, you know,
want to have achieved the highest
accuracy when building applications
using this approach, right? And that's
exactly how I would do it. Now, maybe
for some of you guys, this will be like
a really overkill because it's a huge,
right? You're Let's say if you're going
to, you know, building something from
scratch is a large application, I would
definitely highly highly recommend you
go with this approach, especially for a
greenfield project, not a brownfield
project. If it is a brownfield project,
I'll highly recommend go with one or the
other, right? For example, using
Superpower here to adding additional
feature or maybe using G stack plus
Superpower here to building a larger or
like a semi-large projects. But if
you're going from a greenfield project,
then I'll highly recommend you to go
with this approach. And you can see here
that because this is going to break it
down into different phases. And let's
say if there's like eight or seven
phases, then you have to pass the
prompts continuously starting a new
session to do it all over again, right?
That's going to be really time taking.
And that's why I built a skill called
build loop using the power of Ralph loop
here to basically do this autonomously,
which means that if I were to, you know,
breaking all the phases, like breaking
the spec in different phases, and each
phase has its own prompt. And we can be
able to use that and store all those
prompts into a single state or single
file. So, for example, we have our build
loop here, which will basically
triggered and it's going to look look
through our states on exactly what are
the phases that has completed. Then it's
going to complete the one that's not
completed and basically by delegating
that phase into a hellish session. So,
the basically the way how it works here
is that we if we were to do claw hyphen
p, it's going to do this in a claw
hellish way, which for example, if I
were to interact with claw code, I
usually do something like this, right?
And this will start a claw code session
and I can be able to start interacting
with this approach, right? Interacting
with claw with this approach. But if I
don't want to do this, I want to have
like claw here to run in a terminal, for
example, I can do the claw hyphen p. So,
if I were to do the hyphen p and I give
the exact prompt, I can still use, for
example, if I were to do like one what
is one plus one, it will basically run
in the background and it will basically
try to execute that prompt and that's
it. And the good thing about this is
that I can still run the main claw code
session as this is like the orchestrator
and the orchestrator here can still run
in this command, right? Inside of the
orchestration to basically have it to be
like this is going to be the one in the
phase one. So, if I were to do like claw
hyphen p and just the prompt say like,
"Hey, execute the phase one." It's going
to do that. After it's done, it's going
to, you know, respond it just like how
we responded to for the answer for one
plus one, it's going to give us the
answer here. Once they will give us the
answer here, it's going to do the next
command, which is the claw hyphen p or
phase two, right? It's going to do this
for iteration after iterations until
everything's are all complete. And like
I said, the benefits of doing this is
that we can have our orchestrator here
to basically doing the phase by phase,
right? For example, the orchestrator
here is going to delegate task to a
background job, try to process phase
one, and is not going to take any
context in the main orchestrator. The
only thing that it takes is the
headless session. It's going to run in
the background. After it has completed
the job in the background, it's going to
exit, it's going to give you the outputs
for the results for the summary, and
then it's going to split it back into
phase two and try to pass it to a new
Clockwork session here in this case in
the background session and try to
execute, right? So, you can see that
this way approach is going to give us
the most highest accuracy because the
Clockwork orchestrator here doesn't take
any context for the exact work. The only
thing that it does is to delegate it
into sub background job here to do so.
And for each background job here or each
background Clockwork session here, it's
basically going to, you know, using like
Superpower or G stack, try to execute
those one by one, right? And if you want
to take a step deeper on exactly, "Hey,
how is each background session is going
to work?" You can see that we have our
Superpower here, right? So, basically
we're using Superpower here for for
executions. And usually what it does
here is that it may go through like
planning, dispatching agents, following
test driven development here, and
eventually going to do review and
verifications, right? And you can see
that for Superpower here, if there's any
times where there's like decision being
made, what we can do here is that
usually it will basically try to trigger
back to the orchestrator and try to ask
those questions. And what we can do is
we can be able to actually delegate this
task, right? For let's say if there's
any design questions, we can we can
delegate this to G stack and have G
stack here to trigger like different
personality here to answer the
questions. For example, if they like
design patterns, we can trigger the G
stack here to basically pass these
questions to like different roles like
CEO, engineer manager, or designers, and
try to have them to vote on exactly what
option they want. And at the end of it,
it's just going to take the most popular
vote and coming back to the main flow
and try to continue on going forward,
right? So, this way you can see that
we're not going to have any manual
involvement, we're just going to have
each Clockwork headless session here to
basically try to do the executions and
have it to make its own decisions along
the way. And that's basically how it
works. So, you can see that for deeper
level at the bottom level here, the G
stack is there for making decision if
there's any questions. Superpower here
is the backbone for the execution. And
then for the upper level here, you can
see we have a work scheduler here that
delegated task to each headless session,
right? And each headless session here
has its own fresh context window. And
we're using a route loop here to
basically do this iteration after
iterations. And the way how we have
these phases here is we're using G GSD
to breaking them into different from
phases. And each phase has its own
prompt. It has its own workflow here to
basically do executions. And eventually
here you can see we're also using G G
stack here to basically create a spec.
And that's where the these phases here
are coming from, which is from the spec,
right? That we have using the G stack
here to clarify our intent and breaking
our requirement here into different
phases. So, that's exactly how this
works using the most popular spectrum
dollar frameworks, taking the best out
of all three, and try to piece it all
together into our own workflow inside of
our app developments with the highest
accuracy. And also try to make this
completely autonomous using route as
well, right? So, pretty much you can see
that's exactly how this works. And let
me show you some of the results that I
have getting using this approach. And
finally, just to show you a live demo,
here you can see that we have the entire
build queue is all completed. So, I
basically spun up a clock who session in
this terminal and have it to run build
loop overnight. And you can see that we
have one session, which is, you know,
the current session that we're in, which
is the orchestrator, and it has
completed over 100 sessions in the
background. So, it spun up claw headless
and try to complete phase by phase over
in the background and try to get
everything completed. And you can see
that the overall project here is 16
phases out of 16 is all completed. And
you can see we have the entire uh build
queue here is all empty. The entire spec
is now codified. And if you were to
scroll all the way down, I asked a
simple question, you can see. But if you
were to scroll all the way down for the
context, so for the context window, we
only have spent 10% of it. And that's
why we delegate all the tasks into
different headless sessions to basically
complete the job for us. And we're
keeping all the things that we have in
the current session here clean and
simple. And that's exactly how they
work. We take the specials from all the
frameworks that we have like test-driven
developments, different rules for making
better decisions, avoiding context lot
here from GSD, and eventually piece them
all all together into a single workflow
that we can follow to have a highest
accuracy for building applications
following spectrum developments. And
eventually we can be able to make this
completely autonomous so they can be
able to build it by itself overnight and
using the power of route loop to do this
completely autonomous.